Aminah Burch

Full Stack Developer

Phone: 312.371.5004

Email: a.j.burch11@gmail.com

LinkedIn: aminahburch

Github: aminah-io

Cloud-obsessed Full Stack developer returning to the world of coding after a brief stint in infrastructure guidance. Over 3 years of experience using Javascript, HTML, CSS, and ReactJS to build cloud-integrated customer demos and personal projects. Passionate about modular code, distributed systems, serverless solutions, and the journey of never-ending learning.

Skills

Front End HTML/CSS, JavaScript, React.js

Back End Node.js, LAMP, Ruby, Python

Testing Mocha.js, Chai.js

Databases MySQL, PostgreSQL, Amazon DynamoDB, MongoDB

DevOps Docker, Kubernetes, Amazon Code Suite

SDLC GitHub, Amazon CodeCommit

Work History

2018 - Present Solutions Architect

Amazon Web Services (AWS)

- Used AWS services such as Lambda, Batch, EC2, SQS, and S3 to build and present demos to customers according to their business requirements
- Built CI/CD pipelines for version control and to maintain code bases for internal projects using native AWS services
- Provided AWS architectural guidance and best practices in a customer-facing role to over 30+ customers
- Leveraged HTML/CSS/JavaScript expertise for various internal projects and demos

2017 - 2018 Freelance Web Developer

Amber Simone - Makeup Artist

- Designed and developed initial mockup/wireframe for website using Sketch.io/HTML/CSS
- Redeveloped website using React.js with routing and Bulma CSS
- Deployed static website with Amazon S3/Amazon CloudFront/Amazon Route 53

2015 - 2017 Freelance Web Developer

Mind Muscle Connection

- Developed/built company site using Wordpress platform (PHP, HTML/CSS)
- Setup and configured MySQL product database through GoDaddy platform
- Managed e-commerce business solutions and advised on best practices of Wordpress

Aminah Burch

Full Stack Developer

Phone: 312.371.5004

Email: a.j.burch11@gmail.com

LinkedIn: aminahburch

Github: aminah-io

2006 - 2014 Intelligence Analyst

United States Air Force

- Built & maintained a database to store signal metadata to streamline processing; cut time to find unanalyzed signals by 10%
- Used signal, electronic, and all-source analysis data to create accurate and timely intelligence reports
- Presented mission-critical data to senior leadership, ensuring their knowledge of current theater activities

Education

2015 - 2018 Northeastern Illinois University

B.A. Psychology, Cum Laude

Projects

Tech blog Think About It Like This - https://tailt.tech

Stack Gatsby.js, Lumen, Netlify

Serverless

App

Custom blog/CMS

Stack React.js, Node.js, Bootstrap UI, Amazon Lambda, Amazon API Gateway, Amazon DynamoDB,

Amazon Cognito